{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Muse","incorrectAnswers":["Tears for Fears","Bullet For My Valentine","Enter Shikari"],"question":"Which English rock band released the studio album 'Black Holes and Revelations'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Daedalus","incorrectAnswers":["Icarus","Perseus","Oedipus"],"question":"In Greek mythology, who did Minos hire to construct the labyrinth?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Émile Zola","incorrectAnswers":["Alphonse Daudet","Anatole France","Charles Dickens"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Germinal'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Alice Munro","incorrectAnswers":["Ivan Turgenev","E. T. A. Hoffmann","Alphonse Daudet"],"question":"Which author wrote 'New Selected Stories'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Spain","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Brazil","England"],"question":"Which country won the 2010 FIFA World Cup, hosted in South Africa?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Gerardo","incorrectAnswers":["The Waitresses","Dexy's Midnight Runners","Cheryl Lynn"],"question":"'Rico Suave' was a one hit wonder in 1991 by which artist?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Tehran","incorrectAnswers":["Antananarivo","Yaren District","Amman"],"question":"What is the capital city of Iran?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"George R. R. Martin","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","Jack Vance","Edgar Rice Burroughs"],"question":"Which author wrote 'A Song of Ice and Fire'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Lolita","incorrectAnswers":["Les Liaisons dangereuses","And Then There Were None","Ulysses"],"question":"Which piece of written work starts with the line 'Lolita, light of my life, fire of my loins.'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Ant Man","incorrectAnswers":["Karl Mordo","Quentin Beck","The Grandmaster"],"question":"Paul Rudd plays the role of which character in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Turkey","incorrectAnswers":["Austria","Turkmenistan","Trinidad and Tobago"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.tr' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Indonesia","incorrectAnswers":["Guatemala","Bolivia","Kyrgyzstan"],"question":"Which country's flag fits the description of 'Two equal horizontal bands of red and white.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Sam Rockwell","incorrectAnswers":["Willem Dafoe","Woody Harrelson","Richard Jenkins"],"question":"Who won the 2017 Academy Award for Best Supporting Actor for playing the role of Dixon in Three Billboards outside Ebbing, Missouri?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Algeria","incorrectAnswers":["Ghana","Belgium","Spain"],"question":"Which country's flag fits the description of 'Two equal vertical bands of green and white, with a red crescent and star in the center.'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Spain","incorrectAnswers":["The Czech Republic","Cuba","The Phillipines"],"question":"In which country is sangria a popular drink?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Friedrich Schiller","incorrectAnswers":["Sebastian Brant","Agatha Christie","Rainer Maria Rilke"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Ode to Joy'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Permafrost","incorrectAnswers":["Icerock","Coolground","Evercold"],"question":"What is the name of the soil that is always frozen and helps to define the boundary of the Arctic?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Dream Theater","incorrectAnswers":["Jars of Clay","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American progressive metal band released the studio album 'Images and Words'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Yellowstone","incorrectAnswers":["Yosemite","Sequoia","Denali"],"question":"In which US national park is the Old Faithful geyser ?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Taxi Driver","incorrectAnswers":["It's a Wonderful Life","Apocalypse Now","Life Is Beautiful"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'A mentally unstable veteran has urges for violence after witnessing decadence and sleaze.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Palikir","incorrectAnswers":["Windhoek","Conakry","Bamako"],"question":"What is the capital city of Micronesia?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"2","incorrectAnswers":["10","1","0"],"question":"How is the binary number '10' expressed as a decimal?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Edinburgh ","incorrectAnswers":["London","Bath","Norwich"],"question":"In which British city is the Royal Mile?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Panama Canal","incorrectAnswers":["The Suez Canal","The English Channel","The Strait of Gibraltar"],"question":"Which international waterway was designated as a neutral zone by The Neutrality Treaty of 1977?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Braise ","incorrectAnswers":["Sautée","Roast","Bain Marie"],"question":"Which cooking term stems from the French word for coal?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Houston Rockets","incorrectAnswers":["Houston Thunder","Houston A's","Houston Sounders"],"question":"Which of these is a basketball team based in Houston?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bragi","incorrectAnswers":["Freya","Thor","Tyr"],"question":"Who is the Norse god of poetry?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Jesus wept.","incorrectAnswers":["God Spoke.","No More.","Hallelujah!"],"question":"What is the shortest verse in the bible? (John 11:35)","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"France & Spain ","incorrectAnswers":["Thailand & Myanmar","China & Vietnam","The USA & Mexico"],"question":"Which 2 Countries Have Coastlines On The Bay Of Biscay?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Whelk ","incorrectAnswers":["Escargot","Mussel","Conch"],"question":"The Marine Snail Is Better Known As What","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Harrison Ford","incorrectAnswers":["Marlon Brando","Samuel L. Jackson","Al Pacino"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Indiana Jones in Raiders of the Lost Ark?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Harald Hardrada","incorrectAnswers":["Ragnar Lothbrok","Ivar the Boneless","Sweyn Forkbeard"],"question":"What is the name of the legendary Viking warrior who fought in the Battle of Stamford Bridge?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Nigeria","incorrectAnswers":["Morocco","Angola","Cameroon"],"question":"In which country is the city of Port Harcourt?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hay fever","incorrectAnswers":["Asthma","Eczema","Vertigo"],"question":"What allergy is caused by the pollen of certain plants?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"A cobbler","incorrectAnswers":["A chef","A cooper","A fletcher"],"question":"What is the term used to describe a person who repairs shoes?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Captain America","incorrectAnswers":["Thor","The Collector","Spiderman"],"question":"Chris Evans plays the role of which character in the Marvel Cinematic Universe?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"ABBA","incorrectAnswers":["Radiohead","The Beach Boys","The Police"],"question":"Which group released the album 'The Visitors'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Chris Columbus","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Harry Potter and the Philosopher's Stone?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Isaac Asimov","incorrectAnswers":["Ursula K. Le Guin","Philip K. Dick","Stephen King"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Robot short stories'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Spice Girls","incorrectAnswers":["Destiny's Child","The Pussycat Dolls","En Vogue"],"question":"Which band had Melanie Brown as one of its members?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Stevie Wonder","incorrectAnswers":["Stevie Nicks","Stevie Ray Vaughan","Stevie Winwood"],"question":"Who Released The 70's Album Entitled \"Innervisions\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Pugilist","incorrectAnswers":["Boxerite","Fightman","Brawler"],"question":"What word, derived from Latin, refers to a boxer or prizefighter?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"U2","incorrectAnswers":["Public Image Ltd.","The Script","The Cure"],"question":"Which Irish rock band released the song 'All I Want Is You'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"James Watson and Francis Crick","incorrectAnswers":["Gregor Mendel and Ernest Rutherford","Linus Pauling and Merl Harding","Albert Einstein and Richard Feynman"],"question":"Who discovered the structure of DNA?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Crystal","incorrectAnswers":["Silver","Gold","Platinum"],"question":"In Western societies, what is the traditional gift for a 15th wedding anniversary?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"snakes","incorrectAnswers":["disease classification","prehistoric metaphytes ","society"],"question":"What is Serpentology the study of?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Epic","incorrectAnswers":["Verse","Ode","Sonnet"],"question":"What is the name of the long narrative poem that tells of the deeds and adventures of a hero?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Immigrant Song\" by Led Zeppelin","incorrectAnswers":["\"American Pie\" by Don McLean","\"Fergalicious\" by Fergie and will.i.am.","\"I Write Sins Not Tragedies\" by Panic! at the Disco"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"We come from the land of the ice and snow / From the midnight sun, where the hot springs flow...\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Serbia","incorrectAnswers":["Russia","Sierra Leone","Belarus"],"question":"Which region of the world uses '.rs' at the end of its web addresses?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Nymph","incorrectAnswers":["A Bunny","A Duckling","A Poult"],"question":"What is the word for a young grasshopper?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Beer","incorrectAnswers":["Wine","Vodka","Absinthe"],"question":"For which beverage is the Czech town of Budweis famous?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"St Helena","incorrectAnswers":["Corsica","Sicily","Malta"],"question":"To which island was Napoleon exiled, after his loss at Waterloo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Nirvana","incorrectAnswers":["Counting Crows","Three 6 Mafia","The Velvet Underground"],"question":"Which American rock band released the album 'Bleach'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"J. R. R. Tolkien","incorrectAnswers":["G. K. Chesterton","Philip Pullman","C. S. Lewis"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Two Towers'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Houston","incorrectAnswers":["Atlanta","Settle","Miami"],"question":"The Rockets Basketball Team & The Astros Baseball Team Both Hail From Which US City?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Oceania","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Europe","Asia"],"question":"The country of Palau is on which continent?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"The Painted Desert","incorrectAnswers":["The Red Desert","The Mirage Desert","The Technicolor Desert"],"question":"What did Joseph Ives name the brilliantly colored section of Arizona he discovered?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Republic of the Congo","incorrectAnswers":["Central African Republic","Moldova","Tonga"],"question":"Brazzaville is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Plato","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hobbes","Spinoza","Jean-Jacques Rousseau"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'That man is wisest who, like Socrates, realizes that his wisdom is worthless'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Black","incorrectAnswers":["White","Red","Brown"],"question":"What colour is Santa Claus's belt?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Danny Glover","incorrectAnswers":["Dan Aykroyd","Gérard Depardieu","Shah Rukh Khan"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including 2012 and The Color Purple?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Malabo","incorrectAnswers":["Yaonde","Luanda","Bissau"],"question":"What is the capital of Equatorial Guinea?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"New Zealand","incorrectAnswers":["Hawaii","Japan","Mauritius"],"question":"What land did Abel Tasman 'discover' in 1642?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Wind","incorrectAnswers":["Solar","Tidal","Nuclear"],"question":"What energy does an Eolic power station generate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"France","incorrectAnswers":["Andorra","Belgium","Luxembourg"],"question":"In which country is Normandy?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Robin Williams","incorrectAnswers":["Eddie Murphy","Jim Carrey","Will Ferrell"],"question":"Which actor's credits included Happy Days and Mork & Mindy?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Clogs","incorrectAnswers":["Feather Caps","Empty truckles of edam","Leather cups"],"question":"What Do Dutch Children Traditionally Put Out For Santa To Fill?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Cape Town ","incorrectAnswers":["Freetown","Johannesburg","Port Elizabeth"],"question":"What was The First Town Founded By Europeans In Southern Africa?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Gum resin","incorrectAnswers":["Herb","Incense","Precious Metal"],"question":"What is Myrrh?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Mission: Impossible","incorrectAnswers":["Top Gun","Jerry Maguire","The Firm"],"question":"In which iconic '90s film did Tom Cruise play the role of Ethan Hunt?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Lithuania","incorrectAnswers":["Finland","Latvia","Austria"],"question":"What nation, with Vilnius as its capital, won independence in 1991 after previously being part of Poland and Russia?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Anthony Hopkins","incorrectAnswers":["Tom Hanks","Ewan McGregor","Arnold Schwarzenegger"],"question":"Which actor has featured in films including Thor and The Silence of the Lambs?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Bertrand Russell","incorrectAnswers":["Thomas Hobbes","Jean-Jacques Rousseau","Ludwig Wittgenstein"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'It is undesirable to believe a proposition when there is no ground whatever for supposing it true'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Chihuahua","incorrectAnswers":["Maltese","Pomeranian","Havanese"],"question":"What dog is named after a Mexican state?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Navajo","incorrectAnswers":["Apache","Cherokee","Sioux"],"question":"In 1942, from which Native American tribe did the US Military recruit 29 men from to develop a code that the Japanese never broke?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Macbeth","incorrectAnswers":["Tristram Shandy","Twilight","Ivanhoe"],"question":"Which of these is a play by Shakespeare?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"What's Up","incorrectAnswers":["Rapper's Delight","Seasons in the Sun","I Melt With You"],"question":"What song did 4 Non Blondes have a hit with in 1992?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Jamie Foxx","incorrectAnswers":["Don Cheadle","Johnny Depp","Leonardo DiCaprio"],"question":"Who won the 2004 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Ray Charles in Ray?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"5 Gold Rings","incorrectAnswers":["5 Drummers Drumming","5 Swans a Swimming","5 Lords a Leaping"],"question":"What did 'my true love give to me' on the fifth day of Christmas?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Horton","incorrectAnswers":["Harold","Shirley","Brent"],"question":"In the Dr Seuss books, which elephant hatched an egg?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Baruch Spinoza","incorrectAnswers":["Spinoza","Jean-Jacques Rousseau","Socrates"],"question":"Which philosopher famously said 'If men were born free, they would, so long as they remained free, form no conception of good and evil'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Angelina Jolie","incorrectAnswers":["Scarlett Johansson","Jennifer Lawrence","Charlize Theron"],"question":"Which actress played both the roles of Evelyn Salt and Lara Croft?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"North America","incorrectAnswers":["South America","Oceania","Europe"],"question":"The country of The Bahamas is on which continent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Madrid","incorrectAnswers":["Berlin","Cologne","Dublin"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Spain?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Eve","incorrectAnswers":["Rachel","Miriam","Sarah"],"question":"In the Bible, who was Adam's wife?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"New York City FC","incorrectAnswers":["New York United","New York Hawks","New York Tigers"],"question":"Which of these is a soccer team based in New York?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Beyoncé","incorrectAnswers":["Madonna","Drake","Nicki Minaj"],"question":"Which American singer, actress and record producer released the song 'Lift Off'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Helen Mirren","incorrectAnswers":["Penélope Cruz","Judi Dench","Meryl Streep"],"question":"Who won the 2006 Academy Award for Best Leading Actress for playing the role of The Queen in The Queen?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A herd","incorrectAnswers":["A sloth","A skulk","A cete"],"question":"What is the word for a group of giraffes?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Daniel Craig","incorrectAnswers":["Roger Moore","Sean Connery","Timothy Dalton"],"question":"Who played the role of James Bond in Spectre?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"El Salvador","incorrectAnswers":["Colombia","Chile","Honduras"],"question":"In which country is the city of San Salvador?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Hexadecimal","incorrectAnswers":["Numerolettering","Binary","Ternary"],"question":"Which system of counting uses the numbers 0-9 and the letters a-f?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Texas Chainsaw Massacre","incorrectAnswers":["Halloween","Nightmare on Elm Street","The Blair Witch Project"],"question":"With Which Horror Film Would You Associate The Character Of Leatherface","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Your uncle","incorrectAnswers":["Your cousin","Your brother-in-law","Your stepfather"],"question":"What term refers to the husband of your mom's sister?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"It's alive! It's alive!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Stella! Hey, Stella!\"","\"My precious...\"","\"I'm walkin' here!\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Frankenstein'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Joan of Arc","incorrectAnswers":["Marie Antoinette","Birgitte Bardot","Simone de Beauvoir"],"question":"Who was called 'The Maid of Orleans'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Middle East","incorrectAnswers":["North America","Central America","India"],"question":"From which part of the world does beetroot originate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"As Far As I Remember","incorrectAnswers":["As For All Intelligent Readers","A Free And Indisputable Right","All For An Interesting Read"],"question":"On internet chats, what do the letters 'AFAIR' mean?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Opaque","incorrectAnswers":["Transparent","Translucent","Obtuse"],"question":"What word means that an object is impossible to see through?","difficulty":"easy"},